ROSS FERREIRA MEng

CONTACT



LocationBristol City Centre



Mobile 07972292798



Email ross.p.ferreira@gmail.com



ross-ferreira.github.io



linkedin.com/in/rossferreira

KEY SKILLS

- System Owner
- Project Management
- Supplier Engagement
- New Product Introduction
- New Product Development

TECH KNOWLEDGE

Node.js, react-redux, gulp, es6, es7, HTML5/CSS3, AWS, SASS/SCSS, git, github, OSX, Linux, Scrum, Agile, TDD, BDD, pair programming, code review, PHP, MYSQL, Laravel, MVP, rapid prototyping, Adobe Illustrator, Postman, JavaScript/JSX, Vagrant, VS Code, Terminal, Redux DevTools

HOBBIES



I've been solving problems within Automotive design for UI and UX for nearly 4 years with focus on Machine Learning Adaption. My interest in this Engineering area further sparked my curiosity to further skill and shift my career.

On recently completing a 12 Week bootcamp I am hoping to continue and develop a career within web applications and software design.

EXPERIENCE

2020 Web Developer Bootcamp DevelopMe_ - Hullavington

- 12 Week intensive course in web development
- Projects based on tech industry relevance.
- Industry practices: Pair Programming, Daily Standups, Agile Project Management
- Curriculum covered:
 Full Stack Web development, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap,
 JavaScript, PHP, Laravel, React and Redux. Introduction into
 working with processes and tools such as (Git, GitHub, Vagrant,
 Postman).

2017-2020 **dyson** - Hullavington Advanced Mechanical Engineer (New Product Innovation)

- System Owner- Automotive Thermal Management Division
- Day to day operational management of allocated Graduate Design Engineers
- Daily management of Suppliers, Cross Team Packaging design changes, Test Technicians
- Validation Planning and new test protocols setup, on-site and off-site testing facility involvement
- Managing Assembly KPI's and aligning design milestone to overall project gateways.
- Direct reporting of System KPI progress to Executive stakeholders.
- Machine Learning & Algorithm adaption
- Matlab, Python, JIRA, C++

2016-2017 Mechanical Engineer (NPI) **dyson** - Hullavington

New Product Introduction within EV Automotive HVAC and Thermal Management area.

1

2016 **Cost Engineer** dyson - Malmesbury

3 Month secondment within Engineering Finance Department. This short-term placement investigated cost saving opportunities for various projects currently under development within Dyson NPD. The role further required setting of Project Target DDU's and assisting with various projects business cases.

2014-2016 dyson - Malmesbury **Design Engineer (New Product Development)**

Responsibilities as a Design Engineer at Dyson has required involvement in many aspects of the business including, design, research, testing, preparing assemblies and drawings for tooling and manufacture. The role has given the opportunity to see projects from start to finish.

2013-2014 **Project Manager**



The project management role at Aston included over seeing a unique project for the development of a Hydrogen Powered Urban Vehicle. The role required managing a team of Mechanical Engineers and Industrial Designers through research, design and manufacture. Building key networking skills with suppliers and manufacturers was critical for ensuring the project's success.

2012-2013 Mechanical Design Engineer



Responsibilities as Mechanical Design Engineer at QI required working alongside the Head of Design to provide solutions to various types of vehicle fleet conversions for blue chip customers. This included designing and modifying various vehicles including Land Rover Discovery's that could be used in remote places within the UK where terrain and working conditions are of the toughest.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Development Bootcamp 2020 DevelopMe-Bristol (12WKs)

APM-PMQ 2017 **Project Management Qualification**

Masters of Mechanical Engineering 2009-2014 Aston University-Birmingham 1st Class Pass Achieved

Senior Certificate 2002-2006 Grey College/High School for Boys- South Africa Passed with High Merit